# Jack McKew

0431 670 387 | jackmckew2@gmail.com | jackmckew.dev

Dear Sir/Madam

My name is Jack McKew and I am 23 years of age having recently completed my Bachelor of Electrical Engineering in which I received Honours Class II division I. Please find attached my resume. I am a confident, well presented, mature young man and very eager to broaden my skill set in Data Science/Engineering.

Further to this, I am skilled in software development & data science, particularly in Python, in which I currently author, maintain and curate my own personal blog around these topics, which can be found at: jackmckew.dev.

At my current employer, I have saved approximately 400 hours of working time by automating tasks for a multidisciplinary team. I also have pioneered and lead an internal Australia & New Zealand wide weekly training session on Excel to over 100 multidisciplinary professionals, in which I demonstrate how to utilise Excel and other programs to enhance project quality and improve team efficiencies.

I believe I would be a suitable fit for the position particularly due to my experience and passion for control systems, computer networking, software development, data science, & delivering quality projects on time.

I would be happy to attend an interview at any time to discuss my application further.

Kind Regards,

Jack McKew

# Jack McKew

0431 670 387 | jackmckew2@gmail.com | jackmckew.dev

### **WORK HISTORY**

Current | Graduate Electrical Engineer at AECOM (since Jan 2019)

Undergraduate from 2017-2018

Working in a multidisciplinary team to produce electrical designs in retail, commercial,

industrial, water, defence projects & develop automated software solutions.

Projects involved lighting design, reticulation design, switchboard/switchroom design, communication network design, lightning protection system design, PLC network design,

electrical drafting and site inspections.

2016-2018 Undergraduate Electrical Engineer at Hunter H2O

Casual working on PLC programming, PLC systems, radio networks, SCADA systems,

cable schedules and electrical protection schemes.

2014-2018 | Timber Expert & Forklift Operator at Bunnings

Casual as a timber expert detailing advice to customers on building materials & tech-

niques and operating forklifts in a high risk environment.

Retail experience as a cashier, people greeter and in store loss prevention security.

2015 | Electrician at Downer EDI

Work experience as an industrial electrician, contracted by Hunter H2O to install switch-

boards at various water treatment plants.

#### **EDUCATION**

2015-2018 Bachelor of Electrical Engineering (Honours), University of Newcastle

2014 High School Certificate, Belmont High School

### **CERTIFICATES**

AUGUST 2019 Mental Health First Aider

JULY 2019 ICS/SCADA Cyber Security Udemy

MARCH 2017 Cardiopulmonary Resusitation (HLTAID001)

Low Voltage Rescue UETTDRRF06B

Telemetry Certified Expert Scheider Electric

NOVEMBER 2015 High Risk Work License (Forklift Trucks) HRW726355

## **COMPUTER SKILLS**

Basic Knowledge: UNITY PRO, ISAGRAF, SCADAPACK WORKBENCH, VIEWX, VBA, PHP,

SQL, HTML, JAVASCRIPT, LINUX, UBUNTU, SYSTEM VERILOG, VIJEO DESIGNER, AGI-32, POWERCAD, UNITY, AR, VR, C++,

AUTOCAD, WORDPRESS, REVIT

Intermediate Knowledge: PYTHON, NUMPY, PANDAS, C, Visio, Excel, Word, PowerPoint

LANGUAGES

English: NATIVE LANGUAGE

Italian: INTERMEDIATE (READING, WRITING); BASIC (SPEAKING)

## PROJECT HISTORY

HUNTER WATER 2018-Current

Lemon Tree Passage & Tanilba Bay PLC Upgrade

Analysis of existing site PLC infrastructure & process documentation, development of cutover plans to maintain plant uptime, PLC rack layouts, panel general arrangements

and electrical drafting.

DEPARTMENT OF DEFENCE 2017-Current

Williamtown RAAF Base

Electrical and communications design review, lighting review, site inspections, lightning protection system review

and conduit capacity assessments.

University of Newcastle 2018-Current

Honeysuckle Campus Building 1A

Electrical and communications design, lighting design, cable tray routing, co-ordination with other discplines, Revit drafting and lightning protection system design.

AECOM 2018-Current

Data Analysis Automation Tools

Developed software in Python to automate workflows for simulation software saving 10 hours per use, analysis with minute interval data for up to 20 years, distributed software to multiple users, maintained documentation.

**DEPARTMENT OF DEFENCE 2017-2018** 

New Air Combat Capabilities

Communications design review, fibre budget calculations

and site inspections.

ORICA AMMONIUM PLANT 2017-2018

**Cooling Tower Commissioning** 

Commissioning of new cooling tower at Orica Kooragang.

STOCKLAND 2017-2018

Greenhills Extension

Lighting design review and shop drawing reviews.

University of Newcastle 2017-2018

Chemistry Building Refurbishment

Lighting design review and shop drawing reviews.

**HUNTER WATER 2017-2018** 

Disinfection Optimisation Strategy

Analysis of existing site electrical infrastructure.

Concept design of new switchboards, cable routes and drive arrangement, control I/O and SCADA I/O. Feasibility

assessment for site upgrades.

**HUNTER WATER 2017-2018** 

Dungog Electrical Upgrade

Analysis of existing site electrical infrastructure.

Concept design of new switchboards, cable routes and drive arrangement for site redundancy between switchboards.

WATERNSW 2016-2017

**iSMART** 

Design and development of PLC systems, HMI systems, SCADA systems and telemetry systems. Development of sites such as

dams, weirs, regulators and pumping stations.

FAT and SAT of Site, PLC, SCADA and HMI functionality.

WARREN SHIRE COUNCIL 2016-2017

SCADA Upgrade

Upgrade from Citect SCADA to ClearSCADA. Design and development of SCADA and telemetry system. Designed to function with existing PLC and HMI infrastructure.